# Scott Shepherd

UX and Graphic Designer

scott@scotts.design 206-356-4695 www.linkedin.com/in/scott-shepherd/

# **Objective**

Transition to a designer position in a Seattle technology company.

### Introduction

I have been an Owner/Partner at Solid State Pros LLC, a digital agency, for 3 years. We use an Agile philosophy to accomplish everything from small business needs to tier 1 company software solutions.

**Roles** I've performed in the product lifecycle:

UX Designer

- Creative Director
- Project Manager

- Graphic Designer
- Product Owner
- Video Producer

**3** tactics I use to increase project success and team collaboration:

- 1. **The Amazon Backwards Press Release**: Define your vision and goal, then build the steps needed to achieve it.
- 2. Create **User Stories**: Ground the project in real life and emotional frameworks.
- 3. **Agile (Scrum)** methodology for iterative project development.

Portfolio: www.scotts.design, created using Bootstrap, HTML5, and CSS3.

## Technologies I use

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Premiere
- Adobe After Effects

- Adobe Experience
- DesignInvision
- Sketch
- Zeplin
- HTML5

- CSS3
- Bootstrap
- Github
- Microsoft Office
- JIRA
- Slack

## **Recent Experience**

Creative Director, UX Designer, Graphic Designer, and Owner/Manager at Solid State Pros LLC <a href="https://www.solidstatepros.com">www.solidstatepros.com</a>

2014 - 2017

Notable Projects:

**Stoel Rives LLP: Tombolo,** proprietary software for a tier 1 company used to ticket and escalate incidents in a privacy suite.

My roles: UX Designer, Product Owner, and Client Manager

**Hyla Mobile: TrueTap**, <u>www.truetap.mobi</u> mobile app designed to facilitate the assessment and value of a mobile device and direct them towards nearby resellers.

My roles: User Researcher, UX Designer, Brand Team, and QA tester

**Skybridge LLC:** <u>www.skybridgesolution.com</u> Outsourcing manufacturing company rebranding to approach US tech market.

My roles: Brand Lead, UX Designer, Graphic Designer, Developer, and Researcher

**Merry Go Ride:** Merry Go Ride Prototype Create a style guide, UI design, developer schemata, and clickable prototype for a ride service app for children.

My roles: **UX Designer and Graphic Designer** 

**Lake City Hub**: <u>Lake City Hub Prototype</u> Create a UX design and clickable prototype.

My roles: **UX Designer and Graphic Designer** 

**Epicmeet**: <u>www.epicmeetapp.com</u> Produce a commercial for Epicmeet, an app designed to bring boardgamers together that appeals to its key demographic using a limited budget for live action video. <u>Epic Meet Video</u>

My roles: **Producer, Director, Editor, and Screenwriter** 

**Vett.cloud**: Create a brand, logo, style guide, and 2 animated videos conveying value and explaining the product.

Roles: Brand Lead, Animator, and Sound Technician

- Vett.cloud Value
- <u>Vett.cloud Explanation</u>

**Law Offices of SaraEllen Hutchison, PLLC:** <u>www.saraellenhutchison.com</u> Create a marketing and blogging site for a Law Office.

My Roles: **UX Design, Project Manager, Client Manager** 

#### Project Manager at Motive LLC <u>www.createmotive.com</u>

2017, As Project Manager I facilitated design and development for various client websites.

Creative Director, UX Designer, and Brand Strategist for NED Learning www.nedlearning.com

2016 - 2017, As Creative Director I facilitated branding, character design, graphics, and UX design on various projects. I also run the social media accounts.

## **Education**

#### Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Psychology

Evergreen State College 2000-2003

This included **computer science** courses, logic, and discrete mathematics.

#### Bachelor of Arts in Media Production

Evergreen State College 2000-2003

This included communication, organizational, and marketing studies.

#### Continuing Education

I do daily studies on Lynda.com and other online learning platforms in order to continually improve myself. Recent certifications from these include:

- One-on-One Adobe Photoshop Series
- One-on-One Adobe Illustrator Series
- Sketch for UX Design
- UX Design Techniques: 6 Part Course
- HTML5: Structure, Syntax, and Semantics

## References

Steve Haak: CEO and VP of Strategy at Solid State Pros LLC, 206-407-9689 Stephen Morrissey: Program Manager at Sinclair Digital, 206-475-1290 Daniel Carpenter: CEO and Senior Designer at Motive LLC, 206-795-0189 Kieran O'Mahony: Neuroscientist at UW and NED Learning, 206-499-0176 Paul Clifton: Associate System Administrator at Nintendo, 208-982-7115